(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 1,
"subtitles": 2
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
1st Generation 電脳ぴゅあ推し大宣言
1st Generation Cyber Pure Fave Grand Declaration
ホロライブ1期生 7周年記念！！
限定壁紙・限定絵文字
hololive 1st Generation 7th Anniversary!!
Limited Wallpapers & Emojis
hololive 1st Generation Anniversary Parade
記念グッズ販売中
Commemorative Goods Now on Sale
ホロライブ1期生 7周年記念！！
限定壁紙・限定絵文字
hololive 1st Generation 7th Anniversary!!
Limited Wallpapers & Emojis
hololive 1st Generation Anniversary Parade
記念グッズ販売中
Commemorative Goods Now on Sale
ホロライブ1期生 7周年記念！！
限定壁紙・限定絵文字
hololive 1st Generation 7th Anniversary!!
Limited Wallpapers & Emojis
hololive 1st Generation Anniversary Parade
記念グッズ販売中
Commemorative Goods Now on Sale
ホロライブ1期生 7周年記念！！
限定壁紙・限定絵文字
hololive 1st Generation 7th Anniversary!!
Limited Wallpapers & Emojis
hololive 1st Generation Anniversary Parade
記念グッズ販売中
Commemorative Goods Now on Sale
ホロライブ1期生 7周年記念！！
限定壁紙・限定絵文字
hololive 1st Generation 7th Anniversary!!
Limited Wallpapers & Emojis
hololive 1st Generation Anniversary Parade
記念グッズ販売中
Commemorative Goods Now on Sale
ホロライブ1期生 7周年記念！！
限定壁紙・限定絵文字
hololive 1st Generation 7th Anniversary!!
Limited Wallpapers & Emojis
hololive 1st Generation Anniversary Parade
記念グッズ販売中
Commemorative Goods Now on Sale
ホロライブ1期生 7周年記念！！
限定壁紙・限定絵文字
hololive 1st Generation 7th Anniversary!!
Limited Wallpapers & Emojis
hololive 1st Generation Anniversary Parade
記念グッズ販売中
Commemorative Goods Now on Sale
ホロライブ1期生 7周年記念！！
限定壁紙・限定絵文字
hololive 1st Generation 7th Anniversary!!
Limited Wallpapers & Emojis
1st Generation 電脳ぴゅあ推し大宣言
1st Generation Cyber Pure Fave Grand Declaration
Secret Garden / 作詞・作曲・編曲：宮崎歩(SUPA LOVE)
Secret Garden / Lyrics, Composition & Arrangement: Ayumi Miyazaki (SUPA LOVE)
月夜のセレナーデ
Moonlit night serenade
白い薔薇は誰を想う
Who does the white rose think of?
その身を綻ばせて
Letting that body bloom
愛を歌うの
It sings of love
こぼれ落ちた花びらが
The fallen petals
寂しさの跡を隠した
Hid the traces of loneliness
ねえ早く迎えに来て
Hey, come pick me up soon
最後の一枚が落ちるその前に
Before the last petal falls
今はどんな花とも群れないの
Right now, I won't flock with any other flower
あなただけを待ってる
I'm waiting only for you
あなたとならこの身体が壊されたって構わない
If I'm with you, I don't care if this body is broken
棘に触れたら傷つくわ
You'll get hurt if you touch the thorns
その覚悟がないなら
If you don't have that resolve
いっそここから消えてよ
You might as well disappear from here
重く閉ざしたシークレットガーデン
Heavily closed Secret Garden
夜風はリゾルート
The night wind is resolute
白い薔薇は覚醒する
The white rose awakens
背中押されるように
As if being pushed from behind
扉開いた
The door opened
ただ一人で枯れてゆくのを
Just withering away all alone
待ってるだけじゃいられない
I can't just keep waiting
衝動の赴くまま
Following my impulses
茨の道を裸足で駆け抜けていく
I'll run through the path of thorns barefoot
凛と咲き誇る花でありたい
I want to be a flower that blooms proudly
あなただけを求めて
Seeking only you
会いに行くの
I'm going to see you,
どんな遠く離れていても見つけ出せる
no matter how far apart we are, I can find you
暗い世界も怖くない
Even a dark world isn't scary
あなたを感じるから
Because I feel you
全て失ったっていい
It's fine even if I lose everything
二度と戻らないシークレットガーデン
I'll never return to the Secret Garden
今はどんな花とも群れないの
Right now, I won't flock with any other flower
あなただけを求めて
Seeking only you
運命の糸 私を呼ぶ
The thread of fate calls me
鮮やかに燃える 強い光
A strong light burning vividly
凛と咲き誇る花でありたい
I want to be a flower that blooms proudly
やっとここで出会えた
We've finally met here
あなたとならこの身体が壊されたって構わない
If I'm with you, I don't care if this body is broken
棘に触れたら傷つくわ
You'll get hurt if you touch the thorns
その覚悟があるのね
You have that resolve, don't you?
手を取り合えば広がる 誰も知らないシークレットユニバース
If we hold hands, a Secret Universe no one knows will expand
イエーイ！終わりましたー！
Yay! It's over!
ホロライブ1期生7周年ー！
Hololive 1st Generation 7th Anniversary!
フゥー！イエーイ！
Woo! Yay!
さて、じゃあちょっとね、Secret Garden歌った後なんですけども
Well, now that we've finished singing Secret Garden...
まずは自己紹介、7年目の自己紹介
First of all, let's do introductions. Our 7th-year introductions.
はい、やっていきますか！じゃあアキロゼから
Yes, let's do it! Starting with Akirose.
はい！7年目の自己紹介いきます
Yes! Here come the 7th-year introductions.
ホロライブ1期生の癒し系ハーフエルフ、アキロゼこと
The healing half-elf of Hololive 1st Generation, also known as Akirose...
アキ・ローゼンタールです
I'm Aki Rosenthal.
ハローハローハロー！アローナ！
Hello, hello, hello! Alona!
アローナ！
Alona!
そして！白上です！フゥー！
And! I'm Shirakami! Woo!
お願いしまーす！イエーイ！
Nice to meet you! Yay!
あれ、なんかすごいコンプリートだった
Oh, that was surprisingly complete.
いつもシンプル
Always simple.
恥ずかしい...
This is embarrassing...
恥ずかしくなっちゃった...
I'm getting embarrassed...
なんでー！
Why?!
恥捨てろー！
Throw away your shame!
なんかさ、心のゴボウ...
It's like, the burdock of my heart...
やめてくれ！やめてくれ！
Stop it! Stop it!
みんながいる中でさ、最近普通に自己紹介するの恥ずかしくなっちゃって...
Lately, I've found it embarrassing to do a normal self-introduction with everyone here...
なんでだよ！恥捨てろ！
Why?! Throw away your shame!
いや無理無理無理！じゃあそんな恥を捨てたはあちゃん...
No, I can't, I can't! Then, Haachama, since you've thrown yours away...
見せてあげてよ、これぞはあちゃまだっていうのを！
Show them! Show them what the real Haachama is like!
はーちゃまちゃまー！
Haa-chamachama!
ワールドワイドな最強アイドル、はあちゃまこと赤井はあとでーす！
The world-wide strongest idol, Akai Haato, aka Haachama!
わっしょいわっしょいわっしょいわっしょい！
Wasshoi, wasshoi, wasshoi, wasshoi!
そしてー！
And next!
はーい！ホロライブの清楚担当、みんなのアイドル夏色まつりでーす！
Hi! Hololive's pure representative, everyone's idol, Natsuiro Matsuri here!
清楚？清楚？清楚？
Pure? Pure? Pure?
7年目も清楚にやっていくぜ！
I'm going to keep being pure in my 7th year too!
7年目も？ちょっと聞こえない...
In your 7th year too? I can't quite hear you...
マジ清楚か？
Is she really pure?
最近ね、だいぶ落ち着きを取り戻し...
Lately, I've regained quite a bit of composure...
はい、ということでね。1曲目、シークレット・ガーデンだったんですが、
Right, so. Our first song was 'Secret Garden,'
去年の周年で発表したオリ曲ということで、
which was the original song we announced at last year's anniversary.
あれから1年経ちました！
A year has passed since then!
はやーい！
That was fast!
あの発表からもう1年！
It's already been a year since that announcement!
いや、早いね！
Man, it's fast!
あっという間だね。秒だよ、秒秒秒。
It went by in a flash. It was like seconds.
ホント秒過ぎる。
Really, way too fast.
はい。今回はね、オープニングとして歌わせていただきましたけど、
Yes. We performed it as the opening this time,
今年、オリ曲どうなんですか？はあちゃん！
but how about this year's original song? Haachama!
えー、どうなんだろうねー。どうだろう？
Hmm, I wonder. What do you think?
今年あんのかなー？どうなんだろうなー。
Will there be one this year? I wonder.
はい！さあ、そしてそして、
Right! And then, and then,
何やらステージが。見てくださいよ！
look at the stage! Take a look!
じゃじゃーん！
Ta-da!
どこだここ！サイバーサイバー！
Where is this?! So cyber!
今回のステージはなんと、バーチャル世界の秋葉をイメージして！
This stage is actually inspired by the virtual world's Akihabara!
VTuberならではのね、デジタル感とか。
It has that digital feel unique to VTubers.
あとは、なんかちょっと推し活感みたいなね、雰囲気もあって。
And it also has a bit of an 'oshikatsu' vibe to it.
YAGOやめて！YAGOやめて！
Stop with the YAGO! Stop with the YAGO!
一番光ってんだよな！
It's glowing the most!
そう、一番眩しいんだけど！
Yeah, it's the brightest thing here!
1号店、2号店あるし！
There's a Store 1 and Store 2!
もうもろ秋葉だよ！
It's totally Akihabara!
みんなのね、結構いろんな思い出のものたちがね、
Quite a few things from everyone's memories
いろんなところに散りばめられてるんだよ。
are scattered around in various places.
あ、オリ曲のところもある！すごい！
Oh, there's even a section for our original song! Amazing!
ね、とてもかっこよくて可愛いようなイメージとなっておりますので、
Right, it's designed with a very cool and cute image,
そちらもぜひ堪能してください！
so please enjoy that as well!
そしてさらに！今回のハッシュタグはこちら！
And furthermore! Here is the hashtag for this time!
電脳ぴゅあ推し大宣言！
#電脳ぴゅあ推し大宣言
スクショ、感想いっぱいXでポストしてくれるよね！
You'll post lots of screenshots and thoughts on X, right?!
お願いしまーす！
Please do!
ちなみに、このハッシュタグですが、
By the way, regarding this hashtag,
なんでこの名前かは、最後まで見てくれたらその秘密がわかっちゃうかもしれません！
if you watch until the end, you might find out the secret behind why it has this name!
ホントに？分かるのかな？
Really? I wonder if we'll find out.
これ分からなかった場合はどうしたらいいですか？
What should we do if we don't figure it out?
はあちゃまが責任を取ります！
Haachama will take responsibility!
ありがとうはあちゃま！なんでもする、なんでもする...
Thank you, Haachama! She'll do anything, anything...
ヤバイヤバイヤバイ！
Wait, wait, wait!
ということでですね、このかっこ可愛いステージ、みんなで揃って色々歌っていきたいんですけども、
Anyway, we want to sing various songs together on this cool and cute stage,
まずはですね、ソロパートからやっていこうと思います！
but first, we're going to start with the solo parts!
イェーイ！
Yay!
さてさて、ソロの順番はもうあらかじめ発表しちゃいますか。
Well then, shall we announce the solo order in advance?
OK！1曲目歌う人！
OK! Who's singing the first song?
はーい！まつりちゃん、まつりちゃーん！
Me! Matsuri-chan, Matsuri-chan!
頑張りやー。まつりちゃんのソロはどんな感じなんですか？
Good luck. What's Matsuri-chan's solo like?
まあ、この雰囲気に合った曲を選んだんで、楽しみにしててください！
Well, I chose a song that fits this atmosphere, so please look forward to it!
なるほどなるほど。
I see, I see.
そしてその次は？
And then, after that?
はーい！じゃあ、はあちゃまはどんな感じですか？
Me! So, Haachama, what's yours like?
えっと、モリモリで行きましたのでお楽しみに！
Well, I went with something high-energy, so look forward to it!
新しい曲もあるかも！？
There might even be a new song!?
ええ！？マジで！？
What?! Really?!
おー。さてそして、その次が？
Oh. Okay, and then after that?
はーい、メルです！
Me, it's Mel!
お、どんな感じの曲ですか？
Oh, what kind of song is it?
いや、この空間にぴったりで、
Well, it's perfect for this space,
ワールド、新世界みたいな、地球みたいな、ちょっとでっかい感じでいかせていただきます！
and I'm going with a big feel, like a world, a new world, or even the Earth!
新世界！地球！？でかい！
New world! Earth?! That's huge!
なるほどなるほど。
I see, I see.
そして最後、白上なんですけど、
And finally, for Shirakami,
白上はもう本当に自分の好きな楽曲を歌わせていただく予定でございますし、
I'm planning to sing a song I really love,
何やら騒がしい予感がしますので、お楽しみにしててください！
and I have a feeling it's going to be a bit noisy, so please look forward to it!
おーい！
Alright!
ということでね、トップバッターとしてまつりちゃん、行かせていただきますよ！
So, as our first performer, Matsuri-chan is ready to go!
はーい！それではいきましょう、どうぞ！
Yes! Well then, let's get started. Here we go!
アンハッピー？悩める人の子よ
Unhappy? You troubled child of man
アンラッキー？人ならざるものも
Unlucky? You non-human things as well
今を抜け出してさぁ生きているんだし
Break free from the now, since you're alive after all
目を見開いた過去も
The past when your eyes were wide open
退屈な未来も
and the boring future
カウンセリングやれやれ
Counseling, oh boy
古今東西ピースピース
All times and places, peace peace
アンハッピー？
Unhappy?
アンラッキー？
Unlucky?
ビーハッピー！
Be Happy!
アンデッド！
Undead!
UNDEAD
作詞・作曲：Ayase
Lyrics & Composition: Ayase
ねぇねぇねぇ なんかどうしても戦ってるようなそんな気がするの
Hey, hey, hey, I just can't help but feel like I'm fighting somehow
触れられない
Unreachable
過去の自分自分自分自分
Past self, self, self, self
と思う、とうに死んでる
Thinking that, already dead
透明な亡霊と対決
Confronting a transparent ghost
幼気で痛い記憶の奥
Deep within innocent, painful memories
残念? もういないのに
Regret? Even though they're gone
あれ? そっちがアイロニー?
Huh? Is that irony over there?
透かされているのは現在の自分?
Is it my current self that's being seen through?
ナンセンス
Nonsense
消えないレッテル
Label that won't disappear
Yes! 実はコンプレックス
Yes! Actually a complex
取り憑かれているみたい
Seems like I'm possessed
巻き付いたまま
Wrapped around
ままだ離れない
Still won't leave
ありし日の自分が
My former self
UNDEAD
死んじゃいない
Not dead
お前とお前の連鎖
A chain of you and you
生きていることは変わり続けることだ
To live is to keep changing
不幸に甘んじて
Resigning to misfortune
満足するなよ
Don't be satisfied
幸せになろうとしないなんて嫌だ
I hate not trying to be happy
この世この世は奇怪奇怪ファンタジー
This world, this world is a strange, strange fantasy
次は鬼が出るか蛇が出るか
Will it be a demon next, or a snake?
出会って出会ってやっと始まる物語
Meeting, meeting, the story finally begins
さあ人か化け物か
Now, is it a human or a monster?
閑話休題ピースピース
Digressing, peace, peace
Past & Future, can't change the Past
Past & Future, run for the Future
カットイン!
Cut in!
何だかどうして未来になんぞ何の
Somehow, why, to the future, what
期待もできないような気がして
Feel like I can't expect anything
もう随分生きてる
I've lived quite a long time
既視感とテンプレ食傷
Bored with deja vu and templates
素敵な出来事の気配もない
No sign of wonderful events
積んだ経験の因果が骸骨化した
The karma of accumulated experience has become a skeleton
シワ多き退屈の進化
Evolution of wrinkle-filled boredom
要は刺激が欲しいんだ
In short, I want stimulation
飽きちゃった
I'm bored
慣れちゃった
I'm used to it
ナンセンス
Nonsense
整っていくガイダンス
Guidance getting organized
増えるコンプライアンス
Increasing compliance
蓋されていくみたい
Seems like it's being capped
追憶して
Reminiscing
あれもこれもどれも同じ味がする
That, this, and all of them taste the same
UNDEAD
死んじゃいない
Not dead
お前とお前の連鎖
A chain of you and you
いつの世も過去も未来も今にあるんだ
In every age, past and future are in the now
生きていることを愚直に果たせよ
Fulfill the act of living honestly
目指せハッピーエンド
Aim for a happy end
UNDEAD
死んじゃいない
Not dead
お前に言っているんだ
I'm talking to you
幸せを諦めてしまうな人であれ
Don't give up on happiness, be human
ただ苦しみに慣れて耐えているだけじゃ
If you're just used to suffering and enduring it
死んでいるのと同義、しかばねのアンデッド
It's synonymous with being dead, a corpse-like undead
Unhappy?
憐れむ人の手よ
Hands of people who pity
Unlucky?
目覚めているかい
Are you awake?
Be Happy!
魂を燃やせよ
Burn your soul
生きているんだろ
You're alive, aren't you?
不幸に浸るも
Immersing in misfortune
幸せになるのも
Becoming happy
結局全部お前次第だ
In the end, it's all up to you
古今東西一切合切森羅万象ピースピース
East and west, all things, the whole universe, peace, peace
Past & Future, can't change the Past
Past & Future, run for the Future
人の在るところに温もりいざさらば
Where people are, warmth, now farewell
生き抜けこの化け物がかりの物語
Survive this monster-like story
清く 正しく 美しく
Pure, correct, beautiful
8年目からは、キレイな赤井はあとに戻ることを
From the 8th year, returning to being a clean Akai Haato...
私は
I...
誓います
...vow.
なーんて言うと思った?
Did you think I'd say that?
行くぜのみんな!
Let's go, everyone!
百執念まで踊りまくって
Dance until the hundredth anniversary
止まんねえよな!
We're not stopping, right!
行くぜ!
Let's go!
Good god!
I just wanna live honestly
雑音ばかり That's alright
Only noise, That's alright
I'm gonna go my way, leave me!
Every time I say what
静観してなよ優等生は
Stay quiet, you model students
Fake up 正義の味方
Fake up, ally of justice
(It's true of world)
Isn't it?
You must look at me
(Please, please, please)
Do as I told you
I'm sick of hearing those words
(Just for yourself, for yourself)
I ain't so good girl
(Freeze, freeze, freeze)
Never be lap dog
正論” 的なのもういいって
Stop with the "proper arguments"
「物語に必要」と
Saying "It's necessary for the story"
そこまで言うのなら演じ切ってやるわ
If you say that much, I'll play the part to the end
いい子ちゃんのまま
Remaining a good girl
Yes, Yes, Yes
終わんない No, No, No
It won't end No, No, No
Who is the Villain?
だって I'm a Hero, bye, bye, bye
Because I'm a Hero, bye, bye, bye
イヤになるわ 誰が正義なんて
I'm sick of it, who decides what's justice
決めたのかしらね
I wonder
Oh (Who? x5)
もうどっちだって そういい子ちゃんのままじゃ
Either way, staying as a good girl
はいちゃんちゃん! Yeah
Is just curtains! Yeah
Who is the Villain?
Who?
1 2 3 go!
I give you my big RED HEART
My my big RED HEART
I'll be true to my RED HEART
I give you my big RED HEART
My my RED HEART, big RED HEART
I'll be true to my big RED HEART
My my big RED HEART
いっただっきまーす♡
Itadakimasu! ♡
めちゃゴ三♡完♡全♡食!!
Mucha Gomi ♡ Kan Zen ♡ Shoku!!
ドントカドン！ドントカドン！ドントカドン！
Don-ta-ka-don! Don-ta-ka-don! Don-ta-ka-don!
お肉と野菜をドントカドン☆
Meat and vegetables, don-ta-ka-don!
サクリンパっ！サクリンパっ！
Sakurinpa! Sakurinpa!
カラピッチュ！揚げ物だって出来ちゃいます！
Karapicchu! Even fried food is possible!
ぐとうぐとう だぷだぷ
Guto-guto, dapu-dapu
タラリンチュラリン エビのアジ！
Tara-rin-chu-ra-rin, the taste of shrimp!
はあちゃまクッキング
Haachama Cooking
はじまっちょま～～～！
Let's start!
1. 調べない 調べたやつからサクリンパ！
1. Don't look it up! Those who did get a "Sakurinpa"!
ネットやレシピを見るのは ッダメッダメダメ
Looking at the net or recipes is a BIG NO NO!
2. 測らない 測るのばゴミ！
2. Don't measure! Measuring is trash!
自分量でも作れるのが 一流だろぉおお！
Being able to cook with your own measurements is top-tier!
3. はちゃめちゃアレンジ！
3. Crazy arrangements!
最後はオリジナルの隠し味！
Finally, the original secret ingredient!
これは料理の成長物語...
This is a story of culinary growth...
はあちゃまカレーは 5つ星☆☆☆☆☆
Haachama Curry is 5 stars!
スパイスマシマシで！
With extra spice!
作り方を今教えます。
I'll teach you the recipe now.
めんどくさいので省きます！
It's a hassle, so I'll skip it!
見た目はゴミでもめちゃ美味しい 目指すは世界一！
It looks like trash but it's delicious! Aiming for #1!
※おえぇ...
*Retching*
あなたの胃袋掴んじゃう
I'll capture your stomach!
ぎゅっ。ぎゅっ。ぎゅっ。はい、あーーん♡
Squeeze, squeeze, squeeze. Say "aaah"!
友達 減る 見せたら 減る
Friends decrease. If you show them, they decrease.
左から2番目に 狂
The second from the left is crazy.
正気で美味しい 完♡全♡食♡
Sane and delicious, a complete meal!
お残しした人だーれだぁ？
Who left leftovers?
BAN！ばい ばい おつるーじゅ！
BAN! Bye bye! Otsu-rouge!
It's only love...
もしも願い一つだけ叶うなら
If just one wish could come true
君の側で眠らせて
Let me sleep by your side
どんな場所でもいいよ
Any place would be fine
Beautiful world
迷わず君だけを見つめている
I gaze only at you without hesitation
Beautiful world
自分の美しさ まだ知らないの
You don't know your own beauty yet
It's only love
寝ても覚めても少年マンガ 夢見てばっか
Awake or asleep, I'm just dreaming of Shonen Manga
自分が好きじゃないの
I don't like myself
何が欲しいか分からなくて ただ欲しがって
Not knowing what I want, I just keep wanting
ぬるい涙が頬を伝う
Lukewarm tears run down my cheeks
言いたいことなんてない ただもう一度会いたい
Nothing I want to say, I just want to see you once more
言いたいこと言えない 根性なしかもしれない
I can't say what I want to, I might have no guts
それでいいけど
But that's okay
もしも願い一つだけ叶うなら
If just one wish could come true
君の側で眠らせて
Let me sleep by your side
どんな場所でもいいよ
Any place would be fine
Beautiful world
迷わず君だけを見つめている
I gaze only at you without hesitation
Beautiful world
自分の美しさ まだ知らないの
You don't know your own beauty yet
It's only love
そんなことでもやってみて 損したって
Even if I try something like that and lose out
少し経験値上がる
My experience points go up a bit
新聞はいらない 肝心なことが載ってない
I don't need a newspaper, the important things aren't in there
最近調子どうだい 元気にしてるなら
How've you been lately? If you're doing well...
別にいいけど
...it doesn't really matter
僕の世界消えるまで 会えるなら
If we can meet until my world disappears
君の側で眠らせて
Let me sleep by your side
どんな場所でも結構
Any place is fine
Beautiful world
儚く過ぎて行く日々の中で
In the days that pass by fleetingly
Beautiful world
自分の美しさ 知っている
I know my own beauty
もしも願い
If a wish...
Beautiful World (2024 Mix)
たったひとつだけ
Just one single thing
うらうらら
Ura-urara
君のそばで眠らせて
Let me sleep by your side
Hooo... Hooo...
桜のあと (all quartets lead to the?)
After the Cherry Blossoms (all quartets lead to the?)
All quartets lead, lead to...? Say la-la-la-la-la-la-la
All quartets lead, lead, lead to...? Say la-la-la-la...
やあまた会えたね こんばんは
Hi, we meet again. Good evening
いやこんにちはだっけ
Or was it good afternoon?
広いようで狭いようで
Seems wide, seems narrow
退屈は要らないみたいだね
Looks like boredom isn't needed
ああ問題は依然あって
Ah, problems still remain
頭痛いんだわね
And my head hurts
少しずつと言い聞かせて
Telling myself 'little by little'
願い事叶えていきましょうね
Let's go on fulfilling our wishes
(I shall remember I wanna do, I shall remember)
拾い集めた後悔のかけらたちを
The fragments of regret gathered up
夜が明ける前にラベルを貼って並べて
Before dawn, label them and line them up
希望に変える準備を継続中
Continuing the preparations to turn them into hope
さくらが咲いて散ったその後で
After the cherry blossoms bloomed and fell
何が真実なのかはわかるから
Because I'll know what the truth is
future melody そう今は奏でて
Future melody, yes, play it now
愛が世界救うだなんて 僕は信じてないけれどね
That love saves the world, I don't believe in that though
今目の前の君が明日を生きられるくらいには
To the point that you, right before my eyes, can live through tomorrow
ありえない不条理は ぶっ飛ばしてゆけ with 喜怒哀楽
Blast away the impossible absurdities, with all your emotions
余すな必要ないよ嘘つき
Don't leave anything behind, no need for that, liar
さあアンプリファーは絶好調
Now, the amplifier is in top condition
エレキギターが唸ってる
The electric guitar is roaring
こんなにも歪んでるのに
Even though it's so distorted
心が純粋に求めてる
My heart is purely seeking it
ああ何回も何千回も
Ah, many times, thousands of times
お望み通り鳴らすよ
I'll play it as you wish
君が欲しいタイミングで
At the timing you want
わがままにスイッチを押しましょうか
Shall I selfishly push the switch?
(You can reaction, and play it loud, you can reaction)
はしゃぎ過ぎてた青春時代のいろはとか
The basics of our youth when we were having too much fun
ホコリ被る前に選び出して磨いて
Before they get covered in dust, pick them out and polish them
歌に乗っちゃう番狂わせしたい
I want to cause an upset riding on the song
いっせーのせで魔法も使えるよ
On the count of three, you can even use magic
君は自由なんだから
Because you are free
止めないで future symphony そうお気に召すまま
Don't stop the future symphony, yes, just as you like
不器用でも混ぜ合わせるよ この街に響いていけ
Even if it's clumsy, I'll mix it in, resound through this town
ミュージック、歪なるミュージック
Music, distorted music
大丈夫僕らが試金石
It's okay, we are the touchstone
じゃじゃじゃじゃーん足りない！キックリズムを打て
Ta-da! Not enough! Hit the kick rhythm!
ベース＆ギターおまけに僕が歌えば 四重奏
Bass & guitar, and if I sing on top, it's a quartet
(I shall remember I wanna do, I shall remember I wanna do)
忘れない忘れないよ 今も大人になっても
I won't forget, I won't forget, even now or when I become an adult
だからこの瞬間は楽しませて
So let me enjoy this moment
歌うよ でたらめでいいよね
I'll sing, it's okay if it's nonsense, right?
All quartets lead, lead to...? Say la-la-la-la-la-la-la
All quartets lead, lead to...? Say la-la-la
All quartets lead, lead to...? Say la-la-la...
桜が 桜が
Sakura, sakura
咲いて散ったその後で 何が真実なのかは
After blooming and falling, what is the truth?
わかるから future melody さあ 今は奏でて
I'll know, so future melody, come on, play it now
世界救うだなんて 僕は信じてないけどね
Saving the world, I don't believe in that
今 目の前の君が 明日を生きれるくらいには
Just enough so that you, in front of me now, can live through tomorrow
ありえない不条理は ぶっ飛ばしていけ
Blow away the impossible absurdities
with 喜怒哀楽 余すな全部 惜しみなく
With joy, anger, sorrow, and pleasure, all of it without regret
言えないまま 飲み込むなんて事はよして
Stop swallowing things without being able to say them
with 喜怒哀楽 大丈夫さとどこまでも行くだろう
With joy, anger, sorrow, and pleasure, we'll go anywhere saying it's okay
All quartets lead, lead to...? Say la-la-la...
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
ほいしょ。ということでソロパートでしたー！
Hoisho. And that was the solo part!
あれ？みんな、あれ？ご帰宅してんね、一緒に。
Oh? Everyone, oh? You're joining me, together.
え、何、何その動き？
Eh, what, what is that movement?
怖い怖い！え、え、どうしたみんな？
Scary, scary! Eh, eh, what's wrong everyone?
なんかどこ見てたの？ちゃんと見てくれてた？
Where were you looking? Were you watching properly?
ずっと見てたよー！
We were watching the whole time!
ずっとここにいたんだよー！
We were right here!
うそ、いたの？
No way, you were?
一番近くで見てた。
We were watching from the closest spot.
え、そうだったの？
Eh, really?
どんだけいたのよ。なんか確かに、なんかちょっと今日多いな、とか思ったけど。
How many of you were there? I did think there were a lot today.
ま、ということでですね、ソロパートだったんですけども。
Well, anyway, that was the solo part.
じゃあ、ちょっと一人ずつね、改めて感想などなどなどなんですが。
So, let's hear everyone's thoughts one by one again.
まつりちゃんの「アンデッド」！
Matsuri-chan's 'Undead'!
はい、アンデッドね。やっぱこの雰囲気に合わせて選んだんですけど。
Yes, 'Undead'. I chose it to match this atmosphere.
なんか、この歌詞がすごいMVっぽく出してもらってね。
And the lyrics were displayed like an MV.
めちゃめちゃ良かった。
It was so good.
かっこ可愛く歌えたかな、と思います。
I think I was able to sing it in a cool and cute way.
そしてはあちゃま！
And Haachama!
はい、はあとと一緒に踊りました、はあと！
Yes, I danced with 'HAAto', 'HAAto'!
はあとやばかったよね！
'HAAto' was crazy, right!
すげーキレッキレだった。後ろネタバレててさ。
She was so sharp. There were spoilers in the back.
そして新しく出たね、「めちゃゴミ完全食」。みんな、どうだった？
And the new song, 'Ultra Trash Complete Food'. Everyone, how was it?
めちゃゴミ完全食、って感じの曲になっております。たくさん聞いてね。
It's a song that feels like 'Ultra Trash Complete Food'. Please listen to it a lot.
めっちゃ実写入ってたもんね。
There were a lot of live-action parts, right.
ねー！そしてアキちゃん！
Right! And Aki-chan!
はい、アキロゼはー、「ローゼ」どうだったー？
Yes, AkiRose... How was 'ROSE'?
いや、結構頑張らせてもらったんだけど。
Well, I worked pretty hard on it.
すごかった！
It was amazing!
可愛かったよ！進化したわ。
It was cute! You've evolved.
さあ、この空間でね、こういう演出をずっと、ずっと、やりたいなと思ってたから。
Well, I've always, always wanted to do this kind of production in this space.
ちょうどね、世界観にも合ってるし。ちょっと、すごく頑張りました。
It fits the world view perfectly. I worked very hard.
さすがだったよ！
As expected!
はい、ありがとう。そして最後に。
Yes, thank you. And finally.
はい。最後はね、フブキは「桜のあと」だったんですけど。
Yes. Finally, for Fubuki, it was 'Sakura no Ato'.
なんかすこん部がやたら多かったんですけども。
But there were so many Sukon-bu.
一緒にですね、やっぱり白上バンド曲がすごく大好きなので。
Together, after all, I really love Shirakami band songs.
こちらの「桜のあと」、歌わせていただきました。本当にありがとうございます、めちゃめちゃ楽しかったです！
So I sang 'Sakura no Ato'. Thank you so much, it was so much fun!
ありがとー！
Thank you!
はい。そしてここからは。
Yes. And from here...
ここからはそれぞれが一期生のイメージに合う楽曲を一曲チョイスして、全員で歌うプロデュース曲パートです！
...is the produced songs part where we each chose a song that fits the image of the 1st generation, and we all sing together!
おー！みんな、どんな曲選んだのか、めちゃめちゃ楽しみですね！
Oh! I'm really looking forward to seeing what songs everyone chose!
はい。ま、まつりはね、王道かな、っていう曲を選んだんですけど。
Yes. Well, for Matsuri, I chose a song that's quite orthodox.
うん。
Mm-hmm.
ちゃまはどんな曲？
What about you, Chama?
ちゃまは、可愛い、可愛くて仲良しな曲にしました。
Chama chose a cute, cute song about being close friends.
仲良しな曲！
A song about being close!
はい。なるほど。
Yes. I see.
アキロゼはね、ま、今時感もありつつ、ま、ちょっとダークな、みたいな。
For AkiRose, well, it has a modern feel, but it's also a bit dark.
ダーク！
Dark!
そういう一面もあるんじゃないかな、みたいなね。
Like, we have that side too, you know.
ふーちゃんは？
What about Fuu-chan?
白上はですね、一期生だからこそ染みる曲。
For Shirakami, it's a song that touches you because we're the 1st generation.
あー！いい！染みる曲でございます。
Ah! Nice! It's a touching song.
はい。ということでですね、皆さんもね、コメントなどで予想して、何が来るかなーとお楽しみに。
Yes. So, everyone, please look forward to it and try to guess in the comments what's coming.
お楽しみに！
Look forward to it!
じゃ、いきますよ、皆さん。それではプロデュースパート、せーの、スタート！
Well, here we go, everyone. Now, the produced part, one, two, start!
好きか嫌いかなの人間なんて どちらかといえば好きでした
Humans are either 'like' or 'dislike', and if I had to say, I liked you
乗りかかった船を止めちゃうほど 落ちぶれていないよ わかるでしょ
I'm not so washed up that I'd stop the ship I've already boarded, you know that
予想外の嵐も結構です 泥沼で泳ぎ続け人生満喫
Unexpected storms are fine too, swimming in a quagmire and enjoying life to the fullest
行き先なんて二の次なんです キラ付きが透けてるでしょ
The destination is secondary, your sparkle is showing through, right?
アクセルしか踏まないよ
I'll only step on the accelerator
止まり方なんて
How to stop
必要ないて
I don't need to know
ドリフターじゃ
Just a drifter
涙もエンタメになる
Even tears become entertainment
カメラ止めないよ
I won't stop the camera
ハイ！
High!
不甲斐ない私でもずっと
Even for someone as worthless as me
歩いてきた道がある
There's a path I've walked all along
つまりとても良いことなど
In other words, nothing very good
何もなかったんだよ
Ever happened at all
私 混乱 上々 いつだって
I'm in a state of high confusion, always
ここが最前線さ
This is the front line
最後まで目を離さないで
Don't take your eyes off me until the very end
YAGO
hololive 1st generation
シタイから！ シタイなら！ シタイとき！ シタイでしょ！？ いっしょに！
Because I want to! If you want to! When you want to! You want to, right!? Together!
わたしたちはここにいます！
We are right here!
ここには夢がちゃんとある
There are dreams right here
フレンドなら ともだちでしょ そうだ！
If we're "Friends", we're buddies, right? That's right!
「すき」って言ってみた
I tried saying "I like you"
だいすきっ
I love you!
放課後ならあたりまえのこと
Things that are natural after school
さあさああつまれこっそり帰るな
Now, now, gather 'round, don't sneak home
部活動だね 活動しちゃうね
It's club activity time, let's get active
遊びんでるんじゃありません
We're not just playing around
「ただいま」ってあの子が言うよ
That girl says, "I'm home"
おかえりー
Welcome back!
みんなでいればだいじょーぶ
If we're all together, it'll be okay
部っ
Club!
エビバディセイ！ ともだちでいよーね
Everybody say! Let's stay friends, okay?
シタイから！ シタイなら！ シタイとき！ シタイでしょ！？
Because I want to! If you want to! When you want to! You want to, right!?
だいすき！ ハイッ！
I love you! Hey!
わたしたちはたのしんでる！
We're having fun!
24時間はしゃいでる
We're frolicking for 24 hours
屋上に真っ赤な太陽
A bright red sun on the rooftop
かなり叫んでみた！
I tried shouting at it!
元気でーす！
I'm doing great!
わたしたちはここにいます！
We are right here!
ここには夢がちゃんとある
There are dreams right here
フレンドなら ともだちでしょ そうだ！
If we're "Friends", we're buddies, right? That's right!
「すき」って言ってみた
I tried saying "I like you"
だいすきっ
I love you!
キーンコーンカーンコーン！ からの下校タイム
Ding-dong, dang-dong! After that, it's home time
いえいえわたしたちまだ帰りません
No, no, we're not going home yet
やだよー
I don't want to!
部活動だよ 活躍しちゃうよ
It's club activity time, we're gonna be active
新入部員募集中っ
Recruiting new club members!
ごめんねってきっちりさくよー
We'll bloom properly with an "I'm sorry"
ケンカするほどほにゃららら
The more you fight, the more... blah blah blah
ほにゃ？
Blah?
ネバギバ最強になれーるお
Never give up, you can become the strongest
シタイから！ シタイなら！ シタイとき！ シタイでしょ！？ いっしょに！
Because I want to! If you want to! When you want to! You want to, right!? Together!
わたしたちは経験する！
We're experiencing things!
食べて眠って賢くなる
We eat, sleep, and get smarter
校庭に涼風吹いて
A cool breeze blows in the schoolyard
大きく手を振る
We wave our hands wide
また明日ー！
See you tomorrow!
わたしたちはここにいます！
We are right here!
ここには夢がちゃんとある
There are dreams right here
フレンドなら ともだちでしょ そうだ！
If we're "Friends", we're buddies, right? That's right!
「すき」って言ってみた
I tried saying "I like you"
「好き」って言ってみた
I tried saying "I love you"
テトリス
作詞・作曲：柊マグネタイト
Tetris
Lyrics & Composition: Hiiragi Magnetite
どうしてすぐ知ってしまうの
Why do I find out so quickly?
共振で苦しんでるしっぽ
Suffering from resonance, a tail...
Q. 更新で降る隕石抹消可？
Q. Can meteors falling due to an update be erased?
悪くない消去？
Not a bad deletion?
興味ねえ救い派手感動
No interest in salvation, flashy emotion
常備ねえ薬食べBAD
No stock of medicine, eat and BAD
Q. 超絶えフル見た目暗号化？
Q. Ultra-cute full appearance encrypted?
Q. 金に依る号化？
Q. Encryption by money?
常識ねえ狂いっぱで乱闘
No common sense, fighting while crazy
放置ゲーする陰キャでバンド
A band of shut-ins playing idle games
Q. 送信で苦しいダメCancelは？
Q. Cancel the pain of sending?
Q. 草生えるICEは？
Q. What about the lol ICE?
どうしてすぐ見てしまうの
Why do I look so quickly?
どうしてすぐ言ってしまうの
Why do I say it so quickly?
どうしてすぐ壊れちゃうかな
Why does it break so quickly?
パパラ
Papara
近未来しか勝たん
Only the near future wins
ショッピングモールの現代コンピュー
Modern computing at the shopping mall
小窓　死か負担
Small window: death or burden
モンティホールの経費でピンボール
Pinball at Monty Hall's expense
オイルマッサージ100分コース足湯付き
100-minute oil massage course with foot bath
柚子を添えて
With a side of yuzu
テテテテテトテトテテテテテテトテトリス
Te-te-te-te-te-to-te-to... Tetris
どうしてこんな目に　に　に　に
Why does this happen to me-me-me-me...
興味がないこと本気じゃないもの
Things I'm not interested in, things I'm not serious about
全部後回しで
Push them all to later
知ってることは知らんぷり
Pretending not to know what I know
私は終わってる
I'm finished
恥ずかしい過去知ってる奴らの
The guys who know my embarrassing past
記憶消させて
Let me erase their memories
迷惑かけてごめんってばねえ
I said I'm sorry for being a bother
誰か助けて
Someone help me
妄信ですぐ惹かれちゃうの
Blindly attracted so quickly
狂信ですぐ惹かれちゃうの
Fanatically attracted so quickly
知りたくない知りたくない知りたくない
I don't want to know...
タタラ
Tatara
もう見えねえすぐ惹かれSAD
Can't see anymore, immediately attracted SAD
常動で狂いたてMAD
Going crazy with habitual movement MAD
行きたくない行きたくない行きたくない
I don't want to go...
ばーいばい
Bye bye
臨時休業洗濯ボール
Temporary closure laundry ball
ナイチンゲールの配置ゲーム
Nightingale's placement game
名刺交換の名シーン
Famous scene of business card exchange
借金ボウルでチンチロハイボール
Chinchirorin highball in a debt bowl
温泉旅行3泊4日食事付き
3-night, 4-day hot spring trip with meals
早く行きてぇ
I want to go soon
テテテテテトテトテテテテテテトテトリス
Te-te-te-te-te-to-te-to... Tetris
共感性羞恥　恥　恥　恥
Vicarious embarrassment...
嘘とか粗とか忙しくて
Lies, flaws, being busy
眠れないわ今日も
Can't sleep again today
誰か早く殴って
Someone, punch me quickly
気絶させてくれよ
And knock me out
人生キャンセルキャンセル界隈
Life cancellation neighborhood
ぼんやりとした不安
A vague anxiety
私のせい私が悪いよ
It's my fault, I'm the bad one
そうだよ
That's right
興味が出ても本気でやっても
Even if I get interested, even if I try hard
全部空回りだ
It's all in vain
知らないくせに嘘つき
A liar despite not knowing
私は終わってる
I'm finished
恥ずかしい過去知ってる奴らの
The guys who know my embarrassing past
記憶消させて
Let me erase their memories
迷惑かけてごめんってばねえ
I said I'm sorry for being a bother
誰か助けて
Someone help me
迷惑かけてごめんってばねえ
I said I'm sorry for being a bother
誰か許して
Someone forgive me
絶対アイドル辞めないで
Don't ever stop being an idol
ずっと
Forever
輝いてる君を見たい
I want to see you shining
もっとずっとずっとずっと
More, forever and ever
ステージにいて
Stay on stage
絶対アイドル辞めないで
作詞：指原莉乃 / 作曲：小網準/南田健人
Don't ever stop being an idol
Lyrics: Rino Sashihara / Composition: Jun Koami / Kento Minamida
私がもし君の元離れたなら
If I were to leave you
君はちょっと寂しくなるかな
Would you feel a little lonely?
意地悪考える
Thinking mean things
好きな人がいるのなら内緒にして
If you have someone you like, keep it a secret
ねえ
Hey
神様は将来と指輪をどこかに隠してる
God is hiding the future and the ring somewhere
君の「好き」に合わせたんだ髪の色
I matched my hair color to what you like
私の中君だけで過剰摂取は中毒性
With only you inside me, overdose is addictive
責任とってね大好きです
Take responsibility, I love you
せーの！
Ready, set, go!
絶対アイドル辞めないで
Don't ever stop being an idol
ずっと
Forever
優しい目も真面目顔も
Both your kind eyes and serious face
まだ全てを知ってる私が言う
Still, I who know everything say
絶対 空で輝いて
Absolutely shine in the sky
星は街じゃ輝かないの
Stars don't shine in the city
眩しい君が世界一だよ
The dazzling you is the best in the world
君の夢は 何ですか？ 教えてほしい
What is your dream? I want you to tell me
その夢がアイドルじゃなくても 覚悟はしてるから
Even if that dream isn't being an idol, I'm prepared for it
星のいない空 それが当たり前で
A sky without stars, that's normal
暗い道に目が慣れずに 踏み出すのも怖かった
I couldn't get used to the dark road and was afraid to step out
そんな時やっと見えた光
At that time, the light I finally saw
絶対君は歌ってて
Absolutely keep singing
ただのエゴと分かってても
Even if I know it's just my ego
君はキラキラ衣装が似合う
Sparkling costumes suit you
絶対大きなステージで
Absolutely on a big stage
一列で前で感じたい
I want to feel it from the front row
今日の歌い方 なんか好きだな
I kind of like how you sang today
君の努力 私の愛 成り立つこの風景は
Your effort, my love, this scenery that is formed
強くて脆いの
Is strong and fragile
星の幸せを願った だけど
I prayed for the star's happiness, but
だって君はアイドルよ ずっと
Because you are an idol, forever
初めて目が合った日から
From the day our eyes first met
今日も明日も君ばかりだ
Today and tomorrow, it's only you
絶対アイドル辞めないで
Absolutely don't stop being an idol
(ずっと)
(Forever)
これは報われないお伽話
This is an unrewarded fairy tale
恋よりももっと好きだ
I like you more than love
魔法よどうか 解けないままで
Magic, please don't wear off
はい！ということで
Okay! And so...
ホロライブプロデュース曲パートでしたー！
That was the Hololive-produced songs part!
どうだったかなー？
How was it?
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you very much!
ということで、じゃあちょっと…
選曲1曲目は、まず『キラー』でございました！
So then, let's see...
the first song in the setlist was "Kira"!
めっちゃいい曲だったー！
That was such a good song!
いや、めっちゃいい曲なのに、めっちゃちょっと
激しいダンスだったと思うんですけども…
I mean, it's a great song, but I think
the dance was a bit intense...
いや、もうなんか本当にこの曲聴いて、
絶対1期生これだろうってね
Yeah, listening to this song, I really thought,
"This is definitely for the 1st Gen."
思いながら、ちょっと歌い分けとかもね、
させていただいたんですけども
While thinking that, I also took the liberty
of assigning the vocal parts.
本当に、初めて聴いて染みた…
Seriously, it really resonated when I first heard it...
染みるでしょ？
Resonates, right?
そう、染みたー！
Yeah, it resonated!
そう、もう我々は常に最前線ということで！
Exactly, we are always at the forefront!
やったー！
Yay!
いやもうね、1期生これからも頑張っていこう。
Well, let's keep doing our best as 1st Gen.
最後まで目を離すんじゃないぞ！
Don't take your eyes off us until the end!
はーい！
Okay!
止めるな止めるなよ！
Don't stop, don't stop!
そしてそして、次が…
And then, next up...
はい、アキロゼのテトリスをやらせていただきましたー！
Yes, we performed Akirose's Tetris!
テテテ、テトリス！
Te-te-te, Tetris!
いやこれはね、可愛かったから、
いつかちょっとみんなでやってみたいなって思ったの。
Well, this one was so cute,
I've wanted to try it with everyone someday.
で、グループのね、結構フォーメーションとかを、
ぐるぐるして、はにゃにゃにゃにゃ…
So, I had us do a lot of group formations,
spinning around, hanyan-nyan-nyan...
ちょっと、激しかったですけども…
It was a bit intense, but...
そう、それをね、ちょっと頑張ってもらっちゃった。
Yeah, I had you all work hard on that.
ありがとう、みんな頑張ってくれて。
Thank you, everyone, for working hard.
表情やばかった！
The facial expressions were crazy!
なんかね、めちゃめちゃ痛むかと思ったけど、
「はーい、皆さん！」って。
Somehow, I thought it would be really painful, but
we were like, "Hi, everyone!"
なんか我々はだいぶムスッとしてた気がするね。
I feel like we looked quite grumpy.
ま、そんな一面も愛してよ、ということで。
Well, please love that side of us too.
はい、お願いします。
Yes, please.
そして！
And then!
はい、はあちゃまは『ふれんどしたい』！
Yes, Haachama was "Friend Shitai"!
ふれんどしたかった！
I wanted to be friends!
ふれんどじゃなーい！
Not friends!
というわけで、選びました。
That's why I chose it.
あの後ろの映像でね、思い出アルバム、
気づいたみんな？
Did everyone notice the memory album
in the background video?
よかった！モニター割れてなくてよかった。
Good! I'm glad the monitor didn't break.
思い出になれました。まだ割れてないです。
It became a memory. It hasn't broken yet.
はい、そして、まつりちゃん！
Yes, and then, Matsuri-chan!
まつり最後に『絶対アイドル辞めないで』！
Matsuri, lastly, "Zettai Idol Yamenaide"!
いや、これはね、まあ、まつりのエゴだったとしても、
みんなにはアイドルでいてほしいなっていう気持ちで、
選ばせていただきましたよ。
Well, even if it was just my ego,
I chose it with the feeling that
I want everyone to stay as idols.
この曲もなんか一気にやると、やっぱ染みたね。
Singing this song all together really hit home.
確かに！
Definitely!
染みるー。
Resonates.
やっぱ7年目だから、余計に良かったです。
Since it's the 7th year, it was even better.
お、そして、このパートが終わったということで…
Oh, and since this part is over...
はい！
Yes!
じゃ、そろそろこのハッシュタグの秘密を教えちゃおうかな！
Well, it's about time I tell you the secret of this hashtag!
なんなのこのハッシュタグなんですが、
What is this hashtag? Actually...
新曲のタイトルになってます！
...it's the title of our new song!
ってことはタイトルは、電脳ぴゅあ推し大宣言？
So the title is 'Denno Pure Oshi Daisengen'?
大宣言！
Daisengen!
えー、これはいったいどんな曲なんだ？
What kind of song is it, I wonder?
いったいどんな感じなんだろうなー。
What kind of feel will it have?
楽しみー！
I'm looking forward to it!
いやー、ドキドキでございますけども、ぴゅあ推し大宣言ってことはなんかあれ、みんなの曲ってことかな？
I'm nervous, but 'Pure Oshi Daisengen' means maybe it's everyone's song?
ファンのみんなの曲？
Like, a song for all the fans?
そういうことか！
Is that it?
推してくれてるよな？
You're supporting us, right?
推してくれてるよな？っていう曲なのか。
Is it a song about 'you're supporting us'?
そう、みんなでね。この配信見てくれてるみんなが、私たちのこと...
Everyone watching this stream, you all...
...推しだよね？
...consider us your favorites, right?
えっ、まさか他の人によそ見なんかしてないよね？
Wait, you're not looking at anyone else, are you?
四六時中、私たちのこと考えてるよね？
You're thinking about us 24/7, right?
ねぇ、1期生が推しだって宣言してくれるよな？
You'll declare that Gen 1 are your favorites, won't you?
ということで、それでは聞いてください。1期生の新曲、せーの！
Alright then, please listen to it. Gen 1's new song, ready...
電脳ぴゅあ推し大宣言！
Denno Pure Oshi Daisengen!
は～い、これから配信始めるよ　みんな見てる？
Hi! We're starting the stream now! Everyone watching?
今回はコラボ配信！
This time it's a collab stream!
あれ？あれ？あれ？コメントの熱量　なんだか少なくない！？
Wait, isn't the heat in the comments a bit low?
まだまだ足りない　こんなのっ～～～ん！
Still not enough! Not at all!
推し変は許しませんっ！！
I won't forgive you if you change your favorite!
「わ・た・し」だけに尽くしてね♡
Just be devoted to 'me', okay?
わたしだけに一途
Be single-minded about only me.
中途半端じゃヤダヤダ　噛んじゃうぞ
If you're half-hearted, I'll get mad and bite you!
他の子にちょろちょろダメですよ
Stop flirting with other girls.
よそ見をしたらプンプンプン　おこり！
If you look away, I'll go 'boom boom boom', got it?
めらめらメンヘラップ
Lovey-dovey mental rap.
ほっぺ膨らまし　にらめっこしましょ　あっぷっぷ～っ
Pouting cheeks, let's have a staring contest. Stare...
フクレっ面も可愛いでしょ？
I'm cute even when I'm grumpy, right?
目移りはダメ！ほんとイヤイヤ
Don't look at others! I really hate it.
いつも観てて観てて　わたし待ってる
Always watch me, watch me. I'm waiting.
あなたが推してくれてる愛称の全部が
The love you give me is everything.
わたしをささえる栄養素♡
The nutrition that supports me.
LOVE YOU LOVE YOU　四六時中夢中
(LOVE YOU LOVE YOU) 24/7.
ねぇとってもとってもとってもとっても愛してほしい
Hey, please love me very, very, very, very much.
HAPPY HAPPY　最上級はきゅん
(HAPPY HAPPY) The highest-grade 'Hakyun'!
ほらやっぱりやっぱりやっぱりやっぱりはっきりはっきり！
Look, as I thought, as I thought, as I thought, as I thought, clearly, clearly!
「推して推して」わかってたでしょ？　ぴこぴこ
You understand, right? The barometer of my heart...
キモチのバロメーターも超上がる
...is rising.
「ピュアピュアに　ひたむきに」単推し神推し□推し
Pure Pure Pure, devotedly.
もうホントにホントにホントにホントに　わかってね！！
Really, really, really, really... you understand, right?
おーい、みんな！ここまでついて来れてる？
Hey, everyone! Can you keep up?
この後もこの調子で行くよー！
Let's keep going like this!
うりゃおい　うりゃおい　うりゃおい　うりゃおい！
Uriya-oi! Uriya-oi! Uriya-oi! Uriya-oi!
ちょ待って、なんで他の子のこと褒めるの？
Wait, why are you praising other girls?
よそ見疑惑発令中
Looking away? Suspicion triggered!
わたし以外も気になってるでしょ！
You're curious about others besides me, aren't you?
ありえないよ　ありえない！
No way! Unbelievable!
他の子にちょちょちょっとだけ　よそ見したよね！？
Hey hey, you looked at other girls just for a bit, didn't you?
うわっマジ無理です　DEATH！
Ugh, seriously impossible. DEATH!
ピュア推し信者　わたし推すんじゃ　指切りしてよ
If you're a 'Pure Oshi' believer, then support me, okay?
ハリセンボン×1000
Pinky swear 1000 times!
心変わりしたらほんとに
If you change your heart, seriously...
「推して推して」拗ねる、怒る、泣いちゃうからねー！
...I'll pout, get mad, and cry!
推し変はしてないね？
You haven't changed your favorite, right?
「わ・た・し」だけに尽くしてる！！！
Be devoted to 'me'!
ほらほら　コメントが愛に溢れている
Look, the comments are overflowing with love.
瀕死のHPみるみる回復
Restoring my critical HP quickly.
チート級レベちなパワーチャージ
Super high level, power charge!
ごめごめごめちょ　ごめごめめちょ
Gome-gome gomecho, gome-gome mecho.
LOVE YOU LOVE YOU　四六時中夢中
(LOVE YOU LOVE YOU) 24/7.
ねぇいっぱいっぱいっぱいっぱい愛してほしい
Hey, love me more, more, more, more!
HAPPY HAPPY　最上級はきゅん
(HAPPY HAPPY) The highest-grade 'Hakyun'!
もううっとりうっとりうっとりうっとり　にっこりにっこり！
Enchanted, enchanted, enchanted, enchanted, smiling, smiling!
「ピュアピュアに　ひたむきに」わたしのた日々、日々、推しごと励んでくれてありがとう
Thank you for working hard on your 'oshi activities' for me every day.
「ピュアピュアに　ひたむきに」単推し神推し□推し
Pure Pure Pure, devotedly.
そうぜったいぜったいぜったいぜったい... お願いね！！！
Absolutely, absolutely, absolutely... please!
このこのこのこの！
This, this, this, this!
ん～～～、このこのこのこの！
Mmm, this, this, this, this!
銀河の果てまで愛して（ほしい）
Love me until the end of the galaxy!
わー！
Whoa! Yay!
ということで、新曲でしたー！
So that was our new song!
可愛かったねー。めちゃくちゃ可愛いし、
It was so cute! It's super cute and...
なんかね、もう『推し』って感じで。みんなにも、なかなか...
...it really feels like an 'oshi' song. I hope...
...ぜひ歌ったり踊ったりね、いっぱい楽しんでもらえたら嬉しいなという一曲になってるんだけど、どうだった？
...everyone will sing and dance along and enjoy it a lot! What did you think?
いやもう、やっぱ楽しいね、この曲ね。
It really is a fun song!
前作が結構、白上のど趣味な曲『シークレットガーデン』作らせていただいたんだけど、今回は...
Our last song 'Secret Garden' was quite tailored to my tastes, but this time...
この曲聞いた時に
When I heard this song...
あ、これこれちょっとまつりちゃんにね、
I thought, "Ah, this part is definitely for...
ちょっと頑張ってもらうかなってとこで
...Matsuri-chan to work hard on."
セリフのとことかちょっとね、まつりちゃんに。
For the dialogue parts and such, for Matsuri-chan.
そう、歌詞分けをフブキがね、してくれたんですよ。
Yeah, Fubuki did the vocal distribution.
そうそうそう。だからちょっとキメっぽいとこは
Right, right. So I thought the "cool" parts...
まつりちゃんかなと思って今回はね。
...should be Matsuri-chan this time.
うりゃうりゃうりゃうりゃ...！
Urya urya urya urya...!
あそこみんなよく噛まなかった！偉い！
Everyone didn't stumble there! Great job!
あと、アキロゼセクシーだったね！
And Aki-rose was sexy!
あ、良かったぁ。
Oh, good.
あと、ここ好き「ペンペン」ってね。
Also, I like this part, the "Slap, slap".
お尻叩いて... めっちゃ可愛かった！
Slapping butts... It was so cute!
あと、まつりちゃんに「ちゅっちゅ」ってされた時...
Also, when Matsuri-chan went "chu chu"...
はあちゃま「バーン」ってね！
...and Haachama went "Bang"!
あれ可愛かったです！
That was cute!
はい。そんなこの曲は... この曲は？
Yes. And about this song... This song?
なんと！おっ？
Believe it or not! Oh?
この後、21時15分から...
After this, starting from 21:15...
こちらの公式チャンネルで、先ほど歌わせていただきました新曲、
...on this official channel, for the new song we just sang,
「電脳ぴゅあ推し大宣言」のMVが出ちゃいます！
"Cyber Pure-oshi Manifesto," the MV will be released!
めちゃめちゃ可愛い映像になってますので、ぜひそちらもチェックしてくださいね！
It's a very cute video, so please check it out!
さて、ではここからは告知タイムです！
Now, it's time for announcements!
今回のグッズは、hololive 1st Generation Anniversary Parade！
The goods this time are from "hololive 1st Generation Anniversary Parade"!
こちら5月30日からカートオープンされてます！
The cart has been open since May 30th!
皆さんチェックしてくれてるとは思いますが、内容見てみましょう！
I'm sure you've all checked it out, but let's see the contents!
はい、まずキービジュアルは、オットン先生に描いていただきました！
Yes, first, the key visual was drawn by Otton-sensei!
今年のホロ全体での周年グッズのテーマは「パレード」！
The theme for this year's Hololive anniversary goods is "Parade"!
その中でも我々1期生はマーチング隊です！
Among them, we 1st generation are the marching band!
ではでは、一個ずつグッズ見ていきましょうかね。こちら！
So, let's look at the goods one by one. Here!
まずはですね、プレミアムアクリル色紙！
First is this, the Premium Acrylic Shikishi!
こちら複製サインとロゴが箔押しで入ってます。よろしくお願いします！
It has replica signatures and the logo in foil stamping. Please check it out!
そして続いてはこちら、オフィシャルホロカスリーブ Anniversary Parade 1期生ver.！
And next is this, the Official Holocas Sleeve: Anniversary Parade 1st Gen ver.!
ホロカが入ります！カードもスリーブも1期生です、お買い上げください！
It fits Holocards! Both cards and sleeves are 1st Gen, please buy them!
そして次は、こちら！お、まつりちゃんいってもらおうかな。
And next is this! Oh, I'll have Matsuri-chan do this one.
はい！アクリルスタンド！
Yes! Acrylic stands!
今回のキービジュアルの衣装がアクリルスタンドになりますよ。
The outfits from the key visual will become acrylic stands.
なんとプレミアムアクリル色紙に比べて、それぞれ表情が異なっちゃってます！
Believe it or not, the expressions are different from the ones on the Premium Acrylic Shikishi!
はい、こんな感じですね。そして最後はアキロゼ！
Yes, like this. And finally, Aki-rose!
はい、なんと記念メダル出ちゃいます！
Yes, we're releasing commemorative medals!
こちらなんとケースと巾着がついて豪華な仕様になっておりまして、
These come with a case and a drawstring bag in a luxurious set,
期生ごとにね、デザインが異なっているので、ぜひぜひコレクションしたくなっちゃうアイテムなんじゃないのかなと思っています。
and the design is different for each generation, so I think it's an item you'll want to collect.
タレントカラーと名前も入っているので、ぜひゲットしてね！
It also has the talent's color and name, so please get one!
さて、こちらのグッズなんですが、受注期間が
Now, regarding these goods, the ordering period...
5月30日(金)から、
...is from Friday, May 30th...
今月6月30日(月)までなので、皆さん忘れずにご購入ください！
...to Monday, June 30th, so please don't forget to buy them!
以上、周年のグッズ告知でした！
That concludes the anniversary goods announcement!
さて、ではここからは、なんとまだある！次はメンバー個別の告知タイムです！
Now, there's actually more! Next is individual member announcement time!
一人ずつで、まつりちゃんから！
One by one, starting with Matsuri-chan!
はい！じゃあまつりは周年グッズの告知にしますよ！
Yes! Then I'll announce my anniversary goods!
この後ですね、21時30分から、
After this, at 21:30,
まつりの個人の周年グッズが出ちゃいますので、ぜひぜひ買ってください！
my individual anniversary goods will be released, so please buy them!
超可愛いイラストです！そして、はあとちゃん！
The illustration is super cute! And next, Haato-chan!
はい、はあちゃまはこちら！ドドン！
Yes, Haachama is this! Bam!
「めちゃゴミ♡完♡全♡食!!」
"Mecha Gomi Kanzen Shoku"
本日の0時から、各種音楽サイトでもリリースされるので、お楽しみに！
It will be released on various music sites from midnight tonight, so look forward to it!
6周年グッズも... あしたですよ！
The 6th anniversary goods are... tomorrow!
6周年？ 6周年！？
6th anniversary? 6th anniversary!?
あ、間違えた。7周年！
Ah, my mistake. 7th anniversary!
7周年グッズも、お楽しみに！メダルとハチミツがテーマになっております！
Please look forward to the 7th anniversary goods too! The theme is medals and honey!
はい、白上です！
Yes, it's Shirakami!
白上もですね、グッズが出るんですけども、こちらはですね、6月3日に発売予定でございます！
I'm also releasing goods, which are scheduled to go on sale on June 3rd!
グッズの詳細などはよければ6月3日の配信お楽しみに！
Please look forward to the stream on June 3rd for details on the goods!
あ、そして最後はアキちゃん！
And finally, Aki-chan!
はいはいはいはいはい！
Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes!
アキロゼのでーす！ なんと、
It's Akirose! Surprisingly,
MUSICAL Fantasia of Bremen
音楽 それは私たちの人生に彩りを、勇気を、
そして夢を与えてくれる不思議な魔法
これはそんな音楽の力を信じた動物たちの冒険の物語
6月1日24時～ リリース
MUSICAL Fantasia of Bremen
Music—it is a mysterious magic that brings color, courage,
and dreams to our lives.
This is the story of the adventures of animals who believed in the power of music.
Released on June 1st at 24:00.
2024年かな？ 自分の生誕祭の時にお披露目しました、
Was it 2024? During my birthday celebration, I revealed...
ミュージカル「Fantasia of Bremen」の曲が、ついに発売になります！
the songs from the musical "Fantasia of Bremen" are finally going on sale!
わー！ おめでとうー！
Yay! Congratulations!
なります！ この後24時リリース予定なので、
They are! They're scheduled for release at 24:00 today,
ぜひいっぱい聴いたり、歌ってみたり踊ってみたりして、楽しんでもらえたらなと思ってます！
so I hope you'll enjoy them by listening to them a lot, or maybe trying to sing and dance along!
あと、ミュージックビデオとして、そのミュージカル部分だけ切り取ったものも上げようと思ってるので、
Also, I'm planning to upload a music video that cuts out just the musical part,
アキロゼのチャンネルもぜひ見てください！
so please check out Akirose's channel too!
見てねー！
Watch it!
はーい！
Okay!
はい！ 以上、告知タイムでしたー！
Okay! That was the end of the announcement time!
わー！
Yay!
ということでですね、もう7周年迎えて、
And so, having reached our 7th anniversary,
え、8周年ですか？ 明日から。
eh, is it our 8th anniversary? Starting tomorrow.
明日からだね。
It starts tomorrow.
おめでとー！
Congratulations!
ということで、ちびっこに例えると中学校2年生。
So, if we were kids, we'd be in the 2nd year of middle school.
我々は中2！
We're 8th graders!
中学2年生になったー！
We've become 2nd-year middle schoolers!
あー！ すごーい！
Ah! Amazing!
封印が解けるような、眩しい...
Like a seal being broken, dazzling...
眩しい！ なんかこれ以上解き放たれてたらまずい！
Dazzling! If we're unleashed any further, it'll be bad!
どうなっちゃうのー！
What's going to happen!?
はい、これからも、のんびりやっていく1期生でございますけどもね、
Well, we'll continue to be the 1st generation that takes things at our own pace,
これからも楽しく活動していきますので、皆様よろしくお願いします！
but we'll keep having fun with our activities, so please keep supporting us!
お願いしまーす！ 頑張ろうぜー！
Please do! Let's do our best!
はい、それではですね、またそれぞれの配信でお会いしましょう！
Alright then, we'll see you again in our respective streams!
はーい！ せーの、
Okay! Ready,
ばいばーい！
Bye-bye!
7周年ありがとう！
これからも最強じゃなきゃ許しません！
浮気厳禁！
Thank you for the 7th anniversary!
I won't forgive you if we aren't the best from now on too!
Cheating is strictly forbidden!